quicken.com 2011-06-20

# Intuit Small Business Privacy Statement

At Intuit, we value our relationship with you and place the highest importance on respecting and protecting your privacy. We want you to feel comfortable and confident when using our products and services and with entrusting your personal, company and financial information to us. The full Intuit Small Business Privacy Statement can be found by going to http://smallbusiness.intuit.com/small-business/privacy/#privacyStatement. 

The following Intuit businesses and processes adhere to the US Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of Notice, Choice, Onward Transfer, Security, Data Integrity, Access and Enforcement, and are registered with the [U.S. Department of Commerce's Safe Harbor Program](http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/): QuickBooks Online Global, Intuit Brainstorm and the Intuit Procurement contracting and Purchasing process. 

Click here for more information

  * We collect personal information such as your name, shipping/billing address, e-mail, phone, and credit card number when you interact with us for sales, service, support, registration and payment.
  * We may collect and store sensitive information such as account and purchase information on your behalf as part of the services provided to you.
  * We collect personal information to deliver or allow access to our products and services.
  * We collect information about your system as it interacts with us such as your IP address and browser information.
  * We use common internet technologies, such as cookies and Web beacons to manage our Web sites and services, advertising and e-mail programs. 
  * We collect user feedback, community discussions, chats and other interactions at our sites.
  * We may obtain additional information about you, such as demographic information, from commercially available sources.

Intuit works to protect your personal information from loss, misuse, or unauthorized alteration by using industry-recognized security safeguards, coupled with carefully developed security procedures and practices. We maintain physical, electronic and procedural safeguards that comply with applicable laws and federal standards. We use both internal and external resources to review our security procedures. Your sensitive information, such as credit card information, is encrypted when it is transmitted to us. Our employees are trained and required to safeguard your information. Click here for more information. 

Click here for more information. 

  * We do not sell or rent your personal information with anyone for promotional or marketing purposes.
  * We do not share your personal information with anyone outside of Intuit for their promotional or marketing use without your consent.
  * We use your personal or financial information to provide you with information and services you request, to tell you about other products and services, and to give you a customized interactive experience as you use our products. 
  * We also use the information for support, to develop new features, and to improve the overall quality of Intuit's products and services.
  * We may also use the information to show you a history of your activity, to provide you with statistics about you or your use of our product or service, or to provide you with a better user experience.
  * We may summarize information about you, in a way that does not identify you personally, and combine it with other information to understand how our products are used, to deliver products and services and to help us develop new products and services.
  * We may use service companies to help provide you products and services who are not allowed to use your information for their own purposes.

Update your contact preferences [here](https://privacy.intuit.com/cpi/do/preferences?p_isForeign=0&z=http%3A%2F%2Fabout.intuit.com%2Fprivacy%2F&dialog=0&p_sourceid=5&p_closeoncancel=0&hidenav=0&p_prioritycode=). 

If you have questions or concerns about Intuit's collection, use, or disclosure of your personal information, please contact the [Privacy Team](https://privacy.intuit.com/cpi/do/comments)  
Or write to us at:  
Privacy Team  
Intuit Inc,  
2800 East Commerce Center Place,  
Tucson, AZ 85706  

Intuit has been awarded TRUSTe's Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy policy and practices have been reviewed by TRUSTe for compliance with [TRUSTe's program requirements](http://www.truste.com/privacy_seals_and_services/consumer_privacy/privacy-programs-requirements.html) including transparency, accountability and choice regarding the collection and use of your personal information. The TRUSTe program does not cover information that may be collected through downloadable software. TRUSTe's mission, as an independent third party, is to accelerate online trust among consumers and organizations globally through its leading privacy trustmark and innovative trust solutions. If you have questions or complaints regarding our privacy policy or practices, please contact us at the address posted above. If you are not satisfied with our response you can contact [TRUSTe here](http://watchdog.truste.com/pvr.php?page=complaint). 

Intuit Small Business Privacy Statement

At Intuit, we value our relationship with you and place the highest importance on respecting and protecting the privacy of our customers. To help you feel comfortable and confident when using our Web sites, here are the principles that govern our information practices and other privacy aspects of our Web sites. When we use the words "personal information," we're referring to information that personally identifies you. This privacy statement applies to all Intuit Small Business sites and services that display or link to the statement. 

Some Intuit financial products require you to register your purchase. During the registration process we ask for your name, business address and phone number, e-mail address and company name. If you register online, your software license and version information may be sent to Intuit automatically. We may also ask you to answer some optional questions about yourself and your business and how you use the product. We may obtain additional information about you, such as address change information, from commercially available sources, in order to keep our records current. 

When purchasing some financial services, such as payroll or payments processing, we may also ask for company financial information, social security number, Federal Employer Identification Number, employee information and other information necessary to process the service application or fulfill the service. We may use this information to verify your identity and creditworthiness. If you are signing up for a financial service from within your software, we may prefill some information from your software to assist you in the application process. When you sign up for additional financial services, we may use previous application information to determine if you qualify for other services. You will be able to change or update information on the application prior to submitting. We may also use this information to assist you in filling out other applications for financial services. 

You may use Intuit ProLine tax preparation products and services to assist you with the preparation and electronic filing of tax returns. "Tax return information" is information that taxpayers provide in order to prepare a tax return using an Intuit ProLine tax product. The use and disclosure of tax return information is governed by Section 7216 of the Internal Revenue Code and many state codes and regulations. Intuit discloses or uses tax return information only in accordance with applicable laws, to prepare, assist in preparing, or obtain or provide services in connection with preparing tax returns. 

Disclosing Your Data

Intuit may also transfer personal data to Intuit-affiliated companies in other countries. These may be outside the European Economic Area and may not have adequate laws that protect the rights and freedoms of data subjects in relation to the processing of personal data. Where this is done, Intuit shall take necessary steps to adequately protect the information transferred. BY SUPPLYING PERSONAL DATA TO INTUIT, YOU CONSENT TO ANY SUCH TRANSFER.

COLLECTION OF INFORMATION IN MOBILE APPLICATIONS

When using Intuit mobile applications and services, we may collect personal information from you such as your phone number, mobile device type, and carrier. We use this information in order to set up and manage your account as well as contact you about your services. If you use location-enabled products and services, you may be sending Intuit location information. This information may or may not reveal your actual location. We use your information to process and personalize your requests. We also use the information for support, to develop new features, and to improve the overall quality of Intuit's products and services. We may also use the information to show you a history of your activity, to provide you with statistics about you or your use of our product or service, or to provide you with a better user experience. If you give us permission, we may also use your information to contact you about special offerings that may interest you. If you sign up for a mobile message service, you will have the opportunity to stop receiving mobile messages by following the instructions in the message. 

Your mobile service provider may be required to monitor your messages for inappropriate content, and that provider may pass on that monitoring obligation to Intuit. To fulfill these requirements, Intuit may monitor your mobile messages for inappropriate content. 

If you sign up for an Intuit mobile messaging service through which you have the ability to send mobile messages to other individuals or businesses, you are required to follow all applicable laws, including unsolicited communication laws. 

If you sign up for a third-party application or service, we may share information about your mobile device in order to provide the service you requested. Your carrier may have access to information we collect. We suggest that you review your carrier’s privacy statement and the privacy statements for any third-party applications or services you use. 

HOW WE USE INFORMATION

 _To provide Web Based, Web Connected and Financial Services_

Intuit financial software products are Web-enabled. You can access some of our services from within our desktop products and others directly at a Web site. Some desktop features require Internet access and will open in a browser window in the software, which will pass through an Intuit server before being redirected onto the Internet. If the software cannot find a connection, it may ask you to establish one. When you are connected to the Internet from within the software we may also include product updates and messages, service information and help content in the Internet transmissions. 

If you choose, your software can check our Web site for Automatic Updates. Then the software will automatically check for updates when you are connected to our servers. If you prefer, you can download updates manually from our Web site. When you receive updates, Intuit will receive technical information about your computer's connection and the software being updated. When you access our Web-enabled services from within our desktop products we will note the link you clicked on and we may also collect information about your product, system or other technical data that will help us direct you to the appropriate information or service. Some of our Web-enabled products and services synchronize with the information on your computer to help keep the data accurate and provide additional online services. In some cases, you can manage the frequency of these updates. If you no longer want to synchronize data, you can cancel the service through the service administration pages. 

We may access and set cookies using Web beacons, also known as single-pixel GIFs, which are invisible graphical images. These Web beacons provide useful information regarding our site, such as the pages visitors view. When we track activity on this or other Intuit Web sites, we collect information such as your IP address, browser type and version, and pages you view. We also keep track of how you get to our sites and any links you click on to leave our sites. We do not track URLs that you type into your browser, nor do we track you across the Internet once you leave our sites. We use your Web site activity to assist you by reducing the need to re-enter your data and to help us resolve technical support issues. We may also use this information to offer you a personalized Web experience, and to tailor our offerings to you. Remember, you control whether you receive Intuit promotional communications through e-mail, phone, or postal mail. 

To help us collect site usage data, we use service providers to place Web beacons on specific Web pages and send usage information about that page via the use of cookies. These cookies and Web beacons to not transmit personally identifiable information to Intuit or to our service providers. All Web navigation data is used in the aggregate to improve our product and site performance. 

When we send you e-mails, we may include a Web beacon to determine how many people open our e-mails. When you click on a link in an e-mail, we record this individual response to customize our offerings to you. 

Advertising networks that serve ads on this and other Web sites may assign a different cookie to you. The information collected is anonymous and is not linked to your personal information. These cookies may be used to select which ads you see on Web sites and determine the effectiveness of this advertising. You may choose to decline cookies from third-party ad servers, which Intuit does not control. If you would like to know more about this practice and your choices about not having this information used by third-party ad servers, please [click here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp)

To provide you with services that connect with your financial institution, we must access your online account. We request the user name, password and any other login information that you have set up with your financial institution to enable access. We use your login credentials to routinely update and maintain the financial information you download, to address errors or service interruptions, and to enhance the services we may provide in the future. If we store your login credentials, we will maintain and encrypt them on our firewall-protected servers. Some financial institutions require you to manually update your financial information and re-enter your login information before downloading each transaction. This information is encrypted and transmitted using secure socket layer technology, making it unreadable during transmission. It is then stored on our secure servers. We also periodically receive aggregated, anonymous, general usage information from financial institutions or their processors, including which online services are used and the frequency of usage. This information helps us improve our services and assist us with troubleshooting and technical support. 

Some products and services permit you to grant access and specify permissions for those you authorize to use the service. As a result, we store the personal information of those granted access. This information may include name, email address, username/ password, and security challenge questions and answers. 

Workplace.intuit.com is an online marketplace for Web Applications that run on the Intuit Partner Platform. When the application is developed by a third party, that third party will be identified and the third party’s privacy policy will apply. When applications are developed and offered by Intuit, this privacy policy applies. Intuit also provides a subscription Web site hosting service. This privacy statement does not apply to any Web site of a third party subscribing to that service. Any information you provide for the purpose of registering a domain name will become part of the public WHOIS database 

Products and services under this privacy statement are not "HIPAA-ready" or "HIPAA-compliant," and will not assist with or ensure compliance with HIPAA, the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act. You are solely responsible for using these products and services to comply with all applicable federal and state privacy laws relating to medical or health information. 

We transmit, store, protect and access all cardholder information in compliance with the Payment Card Industry's Data Security Standards. We transmit, store, protect and access all checkwriter information in compliance with National Automated Clearing House (NACHA) regulations. Check payment transactions are verified against, and are added to, National Check Network's check verification and credit reporting database. Your customers' cardholder and check data, including account numbers, financial institutions, expiration dates, transaction amounts and service codes, may be stored and retained by Innovative Merchant Solutions and Electronic Clearing House to provide the product and service that you have requested 

Intuit and its subsidiaries may exchange information about your transactions to fulfill your requests. We may also provide you information about products or services we believe you may be interested in unless you have asked us not to contact you. We offer you the opportunity to review privacy practices at our subsidiaries' Web sites. 

_To provide Community and Feedback_

We provide discussion forums, blogs and other community-oriented features that enable forum members to communicate with other members. To participate in the forum, we require you to register with a valid e-mail address. We recommend that you exercise discretion in posting personal information on these message boards. Any information you provide is accessible by other users. We also have many places where users can provide feedback and suggestions. It is optional to provide your personal information. These submissions are not confidential or proprietary, and we may publish this information in a way that does not identify you personally 

Some of our marketing emails have a "Refer-a-Friend" feature that provides you with the ability to automatically send information about Intuit Small Business Products and Services to your Friends. Your friend's e-mail address will only be used for the one-time distribution of the information and will not be used for any other purpose. 

We offer various Internet chat services. We encrypt our Internet chat sessions and retain a transcript of the session to help us resolve your current and potential future questions. 

INFORMATION SECURITY 

We protect the confidentiality and security of your personal information from loss, misuse, or unauthroized alteration by using industry-recognized security safeguards such as firewalls, coupled with carefully developed security procedures. We maintain physical, electronic and procedural safeguards that comply with applicable law and federal standards. Whenever we ask for sensitive information, such as credit card numbers, we encrypt it as it is transmitted to us. 

Users that you invite to access your Web-based services will be required to set up an Intuit user ID and password before they can access the information you post. Your Web-based services are password protected and we recommend that you do not share your password with anyone. Remember to sign out of your Web-based product and services and close your browser window when you have finished your work. This prevents others from accessing your account if you share a computer or use a computer in a public place, such as a library or Internet café. 

We train and require our employees to safeguard your information. We also use physical, electronic and procedural safeguards by restricting access to personal information to those employees and agents for business purposes only. Additionally, we use internal and external resources to review the adequacy of our security procedures. 

Additional information about our Security program and additional resources are available at: [http://security.intuit.com](http://security.intuit.com/)

At Intuit, safeguarding your personal information is a top priority. Part of our commitment is making you aware of popular identity theft and fraud scams and providing you with information to protect yourself. Although sometimes difficult to identify, you may receive hoax e-mails, such as phishing scams, that look authentic and appear to have been sent by a company you recognize. These e-mails ask you to provide or confirm your sensitive personal information by clicking on links. To entice you, they often claim an urgent or threatening condition concerning your account, or offer you a prize. You should not reply or click on any links in the e-mail or provide any personal information without verifying that the e-mail is legitimate through another channel. Intuit does not solicit sensitive customer information via e-mail. If you receive an e-mail message that appears to come from us that requests such information, please forward it immediately to: security@intuit.com. We will respond quickly to mitigate potential damage. 

THIRD PARTIES 

Sometimes we ask outside firms, or third parties, to help us provide services, such as designing a Web site, sending e-mails, registering a prospective domain name, or analyzing data. Our contracts with these third parties outline the appropriate use and handling of your information and prohibit them from using any of your personal information for purposes unrelated to the product or service they're providing. We require vendors to maintain the confidentiality of the information we provide to them. 

We may disclose, access, or report personal information when we believe, in good faith, we're required to by law or to protect our legal rights. We may also do this in connection with an investigation into a suspected violation involving the Terms of Service, fraud, intellectual property infringement, or other activity that may be illegal or expose us to legal liability. For example, we may be required to disclose personal information to cooperate with regulators or law enforcement authorities or to comply with a court order, subpoena, search warrant, or law enforcement request. 

We may report and share information about your account to credit bureaus, consumer reporting agencies and card associations. Late payments, missed payments, or other defaults on your account may be reflected in your credit report and consumer report. We may also share information with other companies, lawyers, credit bureaus, agents, government agencies and card associations in connection with issues related to fraud, credit or debt collection. 

We work with other companies or developers to provide you with products and services which we clearly identify. Either Intuit or the other company may offer these products and services. We clearly identify these co-branded products and services. In some cases, we exchange customer usage information to establish and provide ongoing service. By requesting these products or services, you are permitting us to provide your personal and usage information to the other company. 

We also may share non-identifiable, non-personal aggregate information about our users with third parties, such as advertisers or partners, for marketing and promotional purposes. Our Web sites may provide links to third-party sites, such as those of our business partners and online advertisers. These could include other services, promotions or sweepstakes offered by business partners. Because Intuit does not control the information policies or practices of these third parties, you should review their privacy policies to learn more about how they collect and use personal information. 

If you are a business partner or a prospective business partner, such as a financial institution or health plan, you may visit an Intuit Web site specifically intended for you. The information you provide on these Web sites are used only to develop or maintain our business relationship with you. For example, you may sign up to receive additional information about our programs, including notifications about new products, features, and events, or to have an Intuit representative contact you. Once you've become a partner, the Web site may include members-only program updates and reference materials. If you are no longer interested in receiving program information from Intuit, you may ask that your Intuit account representative remove you from future program-specific communications. 

If we sell, merge or transfer any part of our business, part of the sale may include your personal information. If so, you will be asked if you'd like to stop receiving promotional information following any change of control. 

Your Choices:

You may change your account and contact information for Intuit Small Business any time by clicking [here](http://support.quickbooks.intuit.com/support/pages/knowledgebasearticle/1008066). 

If you are within the United States, you may change your contact preferences for Intuit Small Business Products [here](https://privacy.intuit.com/cpi/do/preferences?p_isForeign=0&z=&dialog=0&p_sourceid=5&p_closeoncancel=0&hidenav=0&p_prioritycode=). If you are outside of the United States, you may change your email contact preferences for Intuit Small Business Products [here](https://privacy.intuit.com/cpi/do/email). 

If you are an Intuit Online Payroll customer, you may change your email preference in the "Preference/Email Preference" section of your Account. You may also reply "unsubscribe" to any marketing you receive for Intuit Online Payroll. 

To change your mobile contact preferences, follow the instructions in your SMS or other mobile message. 

If you are a member of the Intuit Developer Network, you can update your contact preferences or manage your account by loggin in. 

If you are a QuickBase user, you can send an email to privacy@quickbase.com to change your contact preferences. You can manage your contact or account information by accessing your QuickBase account. 

You may unsubscribe from our newsletters by using the unsubscribe link provided in the newsletter sent to you. 

Intuit and its subsidiaries may exchange information about your transactions to fulfill your requests. We may also provide you information about products or services we believe you may be interested in unless you have asked us not to contact you. We offer you the opportunity to review privacy practices at our subsidiaries' Web sites. 

If we make material changes to any of our privacy policies or practices regarding personal information we will update our statement and post a notice on our site 30 days before the changes take effect. 

Last Updated: 01/18/2011.
